<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi! I&#39;m Oliver. on Oliver Gibbons</title>
    <link>https://olivergibbons.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi! I&#39;m Oliver. on Oliver Gibbons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://olivergibbons.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Currently working on: Concept Extrapolation for Text Classification</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/concept_extrapolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/concept_extrapolation/</guid>
      <description>Concept extrapolation is the process of taking a feature determined during a training situation and extrapolating it safely to work more generally.
I&amp;rsquo;m part of a small team from the AI Safety Hub. We&amp;rsquo;re working in collaboration with Oxford-based startup, Aligned AI, to extend their proprietary concept extrapolation algorithm.
A full project write-up will be uploaded here soon!
Skills: PyTorch, Git, NLP</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotic Manipulation Using Tactile Feedback: A Strategy for Peg in Hole Insertion Tasks [Video available]</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/robotic_manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/robotic_manipulation/</guid>
      <description>[The paper produced as a result of this project has since been accepted for presentation at the 2023 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)]
Assembly operations account for a significant portion of an entire production cycle. Around 40% of these operations can be reduced to a peg-in-hole task. This makes the task a useful starting point to develop new strategies.
This project investigated a peg insertion strategy that made sole use of tactile sensing throughout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indoor Delivery Robot - Path Planning and Obstacle Avoidance [Video available]</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/obstacle_avoidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/obstacle_avoidance/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this project was to develop a robot capable of delivering parcels within apartment buildings, in an attempt to solve one section of the last-mile delivery problem.
Here we simulate a robot attempting to get from a starting position to a recipients door.
Key steps: The robot is assumed to have access to the building&amp;rsquo;s floorplan. A probabilistic roadmap planner is then used to calculate an ideal path to the goal from it&amp;rsquo;s starting point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Oliver. Right now I&amp;rsquo;m modelling carbon credit demand at Trove Research! I recently graduated with a masters in Engineering Science from the University of Oxford, where I specialised in information engineering. In my final years I focussed on robotics, machine learning and control theory.
I enjoy programming and being exposed to new technologies. For a more detailed overview of my background and experience, check out my LinkedIn. You can also see some of my code on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
