<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi! I&#39;m Oliver. on Oliver Gibbons</title>
    <link>https://olivergibbons.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi! I&#39;m Oliver. on Oliver Gibbons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://olivergibbons.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visual Guitar Chord Detection [Video available]</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/chord_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/chord_detection/</guid>
      <description>As a beginner guitarist, practicing became much more enjoyable once I learnt the basic chords because I could pick up new songs faster. To help accelerate this initial learning process, I developed an app that leverages Google&amp;rsquo;s MediaPipe for hand-tracking and PyTorch for training a neural network to identify the chords you&amp;rsquo;re playing. You can see more details about this project on my GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) to create an AI artist</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/ai_artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/ai_artist/</guid>
      <description>This project explores the use of Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) to generate new images based on an input dataset.
I trained a GAN using TensorFlow on the Abstract Art Gallery dataset, which contains thousands of abstract art images, to create new outputs resembling the original dataset. The GAN is made up of two models:
Generator: Produces new images. Discriminator: Learns to differentiate between real images from the dataset and generated ones, helping the generator improve over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concept Extrapolation for Text Classification</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/concept_extrapolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/concept_extrapolation/</guid>
      <description>I was part of a small team from the AI Safety Hub. We worked with Oxford-based startup, Aligned AI, to extend their proprietary concept extrapolation algorithm. Due to IP concerns, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t go into detail about our findings - but you can find an overview of the problem below.
Motivation Suppose you deployed a powerful black-box language model as a chatbot and then, when somebody asked it how to make a bomb, your chatbot answered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotic Manipulation Using Tactile Feedback: A Strategy for Peg in Hole Insertion Tasks [Video available]</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/robotic_manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/robotic_manipulation/</guid>
      <description>[The paper produced as a result of this project has since been accepted for presentation at the 2023 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)]
Assembly operations account for a significant portion of an entire production cycle. Around 40% of these operations can be reduced to a peg-in-hole task. This makes the task a useful starting point to develop new strategies.
This project investigated a peg insertion strategy that made sole use of tactile sensing throughout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indoor Delivery Robot - Path Planning and Obstacle Avoidance [Video available]</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/obstacle_avoidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/projects/obstacle_avoidance/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this project was to develop a robot capable of delivering parcels within apartment buildings, in an attempt to solve one section of the last-mile delivery problem.
Here we simulate a robot attempting to get from a starting position to a recipients door.
Key steps: The robot is assumed to have access to the building&amp;rsquo;s floorplan. A probabilistic roadmap planner is then used to calculate an ideal path to the goal from it&amp;rsquo;s starting point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://olivergibbons.com/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olivergibbons.com/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Oliver. I&amp;rsquo;m a Data Scientist at MSCI Carbon Markets (previously Trove Research). I graduated with a masters in Engineering Science from the University of Oxford, where I specialised in information engineering. In my final years I focussed on robotics, machine learning and control theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
